So usually when we're trying to get information from somebody whether it's calling the airport because
所以通常当我们试图从某人那里获取信息时，它是否正在呼叫机场，因为
you lost your phone or maybe you're calling the owner of an apartment because maybe you'd like to take
您丢失了手机，或者您正在打电话给公寓的主人，因为您可能想拿走
a look or maybe you need to call about some tickets that you booked and you have a question.
看一下，或者您可能需要致电有关您预订的一些门票并且您有问题。
Whatever.
任何。
You probably never talked with that person before.
您可能以前从未与那个人交谈过。
The person you're calling and so it's very important to be tactful being tactful is doing things in
你打电话的人，所以委婉很重要 委婉是在做事
a way which is respectful of others or or polite.
一种尊重他人或礼貌的方式。
So let's look at a couple of really common phrases we can use when we want to ask for information in
因此，让我们看一下当我们想询问信息时可以使用的几个非常常用的短语
a tactful way or ask for information tactfully.
委婉的方式或委婉地询问信息。
So we could say I'm wondering instead of saying I want to know.
所以我们可以说我想知道而不是说我想知道。
Or tell me now you can sometimes say Could you please tell me.
或者现在告诉我你有时可以说你能告诉我吗。
That's fine.
没关系。
Could you please tell me if that's totally OK.
你能告诉我这是否完全可以。
But sometimes if we say yes I want to know it can be a bit too too direct.
但有时如果我们说是，我想知道这可能有点太直接了。
Right.
正确的。
Do you think you could tell me so instead of saying please tell me which is again OK.
你认为你可以告诉我，而不是说请告诉我哪一个还可以。
Do you think you could tell me.
你觉得你可以告诉我。
It's very this is very soft soft.
很软很软。
So this one I'm wondering I'm wondering if you could give me some information about the tickets the
所以这个我想知道我想知道你能否给我一些关于门票的信息
prices for the tickets for tomorrow's concert at your venue a venue is where a concert is held.
明天在您的场地举行的音乐会的门票价格 场地是举行音乐会的地方。
I'm wondering do you think you could tell me the prices for Section C for the venue tomorrow and whether
我想知道你认为你能告诉我明天场地 C 区的价格吗？
or not you have any tickets still available.
或者您是否还有任何可用的门票。
Do you think you could tell me.
你觉得你可以告诉我。
That's very very polite.
这是非常非常有礼貌的。
So you have to keep in mind that one might be in some cases too polite.
所以你必须记住，在某些情况下可能过于礼貌。
OK.
好的。
I'm trying to find out now.
我现在正试图找出答案。
This is maybe when you would have asked several people before and not been successful you might use
这可能是当您之前询问过几个人但没有成功时，您可能会使用
this one.
这个。
Yeah I'm trying to find out whether there are still any tickets available for the concert tomorrow.
是的，我想知道明天的音乐会是否还有门票。
But the last person I called didn't know.
但我打电话的最后一个人不知道。
So they gave me your number.
所以他们给了我你的电话号码。
I'm trying to find out if there are any tickets still available.
我想知道是否还有可用的票。
OK.
好的。
I'd like to know.
我想知道。
Yeah.
是的。
I'd like to know if there are any tickets still available for the concert tomorrow night especially
我想知道明天晚上的音乐会是否还有门票，尤其是
in Section C.
在 C 节中。
OK this is a way to ask even though you're saying I'd like to know you're not really asking a question
好的，即使你说我想知道你并不是真的在问问题，这是一种提问的方式
but after you say what it is you'd like to know.
但在你说出你想知道的是什么之后。
That means please tell me.
这意味着请告诉我。
So by using I'd like to know even though it isn't a question they're going to tell you what you'd like
所以通过使用我想知道，即使这不是一个问题，他们会告诉你你想要什么
to know if they know it.
知道他们是否知道。
So it's kind of suggested there.
所以这里有点建议。
It doesn't have to be a question and it's the same for it's the same for this one.
这不一定是一个问题，对于这个问题也是一样的。
Right.
正确的。
This is a question do you think.
这是一个你认为的问题。
OK.
好的。
But these three one two three are all statements that are ways to say what we want in a polite way and
但是这三一二三都是以礼貌的方式表达我们想要的方式的陈述，并且
then we get the information back.
然后我们得到信息。
I'm inquiring about.
我在打听。
I'm inquiring about this one actually uses the word for today's topic.
我在询问这个实际上是用今天的话题这个词。
Yeah I'm inquiring about whether or not whether or not there are still tickets available for tomorrow's
是的，我正在询问明天是否还有票
for tomorrow's concert.
明天的演唱会。
Yes there are.
是的，有。
Oh that's great.
哦，太好了。
Now I'm wondering if you have any tickets available still in Section C in Section C.
现在我想知道您是否在 C 区的 C 区还有可用的门票。
Oh yes we do actually.
哦，是的，我们确实这样做了。
Oh that's great.
哦，太好了。
Well that's great.
那太好了。
I'd like to know I'd like to know the price of the tickets if that's possible.
如果可能的话，我想知道门票的价格。
So you can use these even if it's within one phone call within one situation you can use several of
因此，即使在一种情况下的一个电话中，您也可以使用这些，您可以使用几个
these as a way to get that information in a very polite way.
这些是一种以非常礼貌的方式获取该信息的方式。
And when you show others respect when you are tactful when you express things in a way which is a little
当你表现出尊重他人时 当你委婉地表达事物时
less direct then usually people want to help you and they may even go out of their way for have room
没有那么直接，通常人们想帮助你，他们甚至可能会为了有空间而竭尽全力
to write this out of their way to help you.
写这个他们的方式来帮助你。
That means they might do more than they would normally do because you're being so so polite so respectful
这意味着他们可能会比平时做得更多，因为你是如此有礼貌，如此尊重
of their time right.
他们的时间对。
Sometimes we can use a couple other phrases we could say someone goes above and beyond above and beyond
有时我们可以使用其他一些短语，我们可以说某人超越了超越
for you or above and beyond what you you expect them to do right.
为您或超出您期望他们正确地做的事情。
Or they they go the extra mile.
或者他们会加倍努力。
These two both mean that someone or you are willing to do more than what normally you or they would
这两个都意味着某人或您愿意做的比通常您或他们愿意做的更多
do.
做。
And for whatever reason you're a very helpful person.
无论出于何种原因，你都是一个非常乐于助人的人。
So if someone remembers that person later let's say they worked and called five people to get me my
所以如果后来有人记得那个人，假设他们工作并打电话给五个人来找我
tickets and it was not easy for them.
门票，这对他们来说并不容易。
They didn't have to do that.
他们不必那样做。
I could say well thank you for going the extra mile for me to get these tickets.
我可以说谢谢你为我买这些票付出了额外的努力。
Really means a lot to me.
对我来说真的很重要。
I really appreciate that.
我非常感谢。
It means a lot to me.
它对我意义重大。
Aw thank you for going above and beyond.
哦，谢谢你超越。
Aw she really went above and beyond to get me those tickets.
哦，她真的不遗余力地给我买了那些票。
I was really grateful all of these are common and basically the idea is when we have or or need to make
我真的很感激所有这些都是常见的，基本上这个想法是当我们有或需要做
an inquiry we should be tactful.
询问我们应该委婉。